Hugo So

Software Engineer

hugososoca@gmail.com — +1 647 234 9957 — Toronto, Canada

Linkedin — Portfolio

ABOUT ME

As a motivated and fast-learning software engineer with 2 years of full-stack development experience, I excel in addressing complex system design, architecture, and framework challenges. I thrive both independently and as part of a team, consistently striving to achieve team objectives on time. My strong communication skills enhance collaboration and effective information sharing within diverse global teams.

EDUCATION

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University

Hong Kong

Bachelor of Science(Hons) in Computing, AGPA: 3.11/4.0

Sep. 2021 - July 2023

Vocational Training Council

Hong Kong

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering, CGPA: 3.87/4.0

Sep. 2019 - July 2021

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

July 2023 – June 2024

E2open

Hong Kong

- Developed a Global Search Service using Java, Spring Boot, Apache Solr, Maven, and Angular for 1M structural data
- Maintaining a large supply chain core system using Java and internal libraries

Backend Programmer

June. 2023 - July. 2023

Virtual Gaming Technology Limited

Hong Kong

- Revamp the core platform from Java Spring Boot to Golang and improve the performance by using Goroutines for 5k-10k rps
- Handling WebSocket and Kafka Consumer services

Part Time Software Engineer

June 2022 – Feb 2023

Dayta AI Limited

Hong Kong

- Developed the internal admin panel web app using Golang, Gorm, Echo, Node.js, React, Redux, and using microservice architecture
- Revamped the B2C Public API service using Json Web Token(JWT)

Projects

Decentralised Bookstore | Golang, Gorm, PostgreSQL, React, Solidity, go-ethereum, IPFS | Sep 2022 - May 2023

• Developed a full-stack decentralized e-commerce bookstore web application enabling online payments via cryptocurrency on the Ethereum chain. Utilized Echo to serve a REST API and React for the frontend, with smart contracts deployed using Hardhat.

CASL Mall Application | Node.js, BigQuery, Firebase Analytics, Google Data Studio, Ionic Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Developed a shopping mall web application to show the shop information and designed a shopping coupon
- Developed a Customer Relationship Management(CRM) system to show the chart of user behavior data analysis

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Node.js, Javascript, Golang, SQL, Typescript, HTML/CSS, Python

Frameworks: React, Angular, Gorm, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, Jquery, Bootstrap, Echo, Junit

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, RDBMS

Developer Tools: Git, VS Code, Docker, Jira, Slack, Bamboo, Confluence, Bitbucket

Honors & Awards

- Third Place in IEEE Web3.0 Developer Hackathon
- HKSAR Government Scholarship for Outstanding Performance